Eric Taft

5750 Dow Ave. Apt 215 Alexandria, Va 22304 (703) 244-1235 Erict54757@gmail.com GitHub Portfolio HackerRank

SKILLS

Amazon Web Services, ec2 instance, Nginx, Node.js, JavaScript, HTML5, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), CSS3, Bootstrap, Materialize, Semantic UI, React-Redux, Github, SQL, Communication, Handlebars.js, Heroku, Back-End Web Development, Sass, React, Passport JS, C#,Asp.net, AWS, Web Sockets, Testing.

Latest Project

BarberShop React App

A Web Application to support small businesses in appointment handling, employee scheduling, and to serve as a web page for customers to make appointments. This app incorporates React and Sass with a Materialize framework for an interactive and visually appealing front-end. The back-end utilizes an Amazon Ec2 instance, Https, RDS (AWS) with Passport for authentication, Express, and an Nginx reverse proxy for security and scalability. The frontend is serverless on Amazon Amplify.

View The Site

Code sample on request.

EXPERIENCE

Self-Employed

Project Consultant and Home Inspection Subcontractor

FEB 2020-PRESENT

Assisting homeowners in navigating their property insurance claims process and negotiating on behalf of the homeowner to produce the best outcome of the claim. Writing building estimates that conform to all local building codes and contracting inspection services and ladder assists.

Power Energy LLC Crude Oil Hauler

MAR 2019-DEC 2019

Responsible for compliance with all Dot regulations, compliance with all safety rules at various oil and gas refineries, and keeping neat and orderly paperwork for all business connected with the truck I was driving.

Summary

Having completed the rigorous coursework of the UNCC's Coding Bootcamp, I've enjoyed freelancing, working on my own projects, and pursuing new career opportunities. My code is available for review at: https://github.com/erict54757. My portfolio can be viewed at: https://erict54757.github.io/portfolio/.

Awards

Top Shot Award in Basic training
Achieved the highest score in Basic Rifle
Marksmanship out of over 200 fellow
enlisted soldiers.

Entrepreneurial Experience

Self-Employed, Eau Claire, WI *Professional Amazon Seller*

Feb2 015-Dec 2016
Creating listings, Sourcing new products, Shipping orders, Maintaining inventory, Finding creative ways to lower costs, Responding to customers, Managing returns, and Keeping financial accounting were all responsibilities I had in successfully running this business. Gross Sales in my second year of 100K with an average profit margin from 20-30%.

Wisconsin Army National Guard, New Richmond Infantryman/Supply Specialist

OCT 2010 - OCT 2017

I have served three years as an Infantryman, training with various light Infantry weapon systems and Tactics. The last four years dealing with logistics, inventory, troop and supply transport as a supply specialist.

EDUCATION

UNCC- Coding Boot Camp

SEPT 2018-NOV 2018

Coding boot camp that brought me from having zero knowledge of Software Development to being proficient at Node js, Javascript, jQuery, Css, Bootstrap Framework, Git, Heroku, React. Please visit my Portfolio on GitPages to see the work I have done to date. GitHub Portfolio

UW Eau Claire-Biology and Business

SEPT 2014-DEC 2014

One Semester of Biology, Accounting and Spanish 2, and Statistics.

UW Barron County, Rice Lake — *Liberal Arts*

SEPT 2011 - MAY 2014

Three Years of General studies Focused on Math & Chemistry.